我是奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来只有一个目标
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
To save my city.
但要达到目标  我不能像过去一样成为凶手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了纪念我的朋友  我只能伪装成另一个人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
成为另一个存在
I must be something else.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
斯莱德
Slade!
我需要一个有能力修船的人
I need someone qualified to fix this boat.
我希望亨德里克先生跟你在一起
I sure hope a Mr. Hendrik is there with you.
我死也不会回去的
There's no way in hell I'm going back there.
拜托  把枪放下
Please, put the gun down!
在你了解什么叫彻底绝望前
You cannot die until you have known
我不会让你死的
complete despair.
你会了解的  我向你承诺
And you will, I promise.
远离西娅
Stay away from Thea.
不  我做不到
No...I can't!
她在你身边的时候非常不安全  你爱她
She's not safe when she's around you. You love her,
所以你要按我说的做
and that's why you're going to do what I'm asking.
这是个危险的城市
It's a dangerous city.
威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson?
叫我斯莱德就行
Call me Slade.
你的睫毛膏花了
Your mascara is running.
谢谢
Thank you.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我不知道
I don't know.
是我的男友
It's my boyfriend.
现在是前男友了
Ex-boyfriend now.
他突然决定和我分手
He just completely out of nowhere decides to end things.
我太了解心碎这回事了
Heartbreak is something I know all too well.
一旦心碎很难恢复的
It's not an easy thing to recover from.
有时永远都好不了
Sometimes you never do.
我们不是在...
Um, we're not at--
这不是我家
This isn't my home.
你不回家  西娅
You're not going home, Thea.
下车
Get out.
Get out!
你好  西娅
Hello, Thea.
见到你真高兴
It's a pleasure to meet you.
星城哨兵
没时间了
No time.
今年  你放那些坏人一条生路
You letting the bad guys stay alive this year
把监狱都塞满了
has filled the jails up to capacity.
是啊
Yeah.
准备好了吗
Ready?
我一直在和莎拉练习
Well, I've been working with Sara,
但我没天赋
but I'm not exactly a natural.
我以前也没有
Neither was I.
好吧  我们要忙活了
Ok. We have some work to do.
抱歉  我今天
Sorry, I'm just having a
很难专注于我们要干的事
hard time keeping my head in the game today.
因为西娅
Thea?
我一直在想
I just can't stop thinking
如果我告诉她真相  最糟糕的后果会是什么
what's the worst that can happen if I just told her the truth?
我告诉了一个人真相  而他被闪电击中了
Well, I told a guy the truth and he got struck by lightning.
说句公道话
To be fair,
从统计学角度来看  也许不会再发生了
probably won't happen again, statistically.
告诉西娅真相不会让她更安全
Telling Thea the truth won't make her safer.
反而恰恰相反
Just the opposite.
罗伊  我们做的事很危险
What we're doing, Roy, it's dangerous.
任何在我们身边的人都可能受伤
And anyone that is even in our orbit can get hurt.
再试试
Try again.
这次
This time...
瞄准了
Aim.
那是什么
What are those?
奎恩企业一个月的手机短信
About a month's worth of phone messages from Queen Consolidated.
扔了
Toss them.
上个月的手机短信我也扔了
That's what I did with last month's phone messages.
斯莱德还逍遥法外  我没空管公司的事
With Slade out there, I don't have time for the company.
你得腾出时间  奥利弗
Well, you have to make time, Oliver.
至少三小时
At least three hours.
年度董事会
The annual board meeting.
总裁不可能不出席的
There's absolutely zero way that the CEO can avoid being there.
我知道有一阵子了
And I know it's been a while,
所以别忘了  总裁是你
so in case you've forgotten, that's you.
你记得把西装放哪儿了吗
Do you remember where you put your business suit?
或者你把西装也放在很酷的玻璃盒里了
Or do you keep it in a cool glass case, too?
我要把你们都杀了
I'm going to kill all of you!
这不是私人恩怨
This is not personal.
也许有点吧
Well, maybe a little.
不是
It's not.
这是为了生存
This is about survival.
生存  这样说谋杀真好听啊
Survival. What a noble word for murder.
斯莱德让我们别无选择
Slade gave us no option.
亨德里克换奥利弗
Hendrik for Oliver.
我们有什么权力决定
And what gives any of us the right to decide
谁的生命更有价值
one's life is more valuable than another?
他被绑起来了  我们没有
He is tied up. We are not.
一旦他修好了船
Once he gets the boat working,
斯莱德就不需要他了
Slade will have no more need for him.
我们别自欺欺人了
So let's not kid ourselves.
这样做就等于判了亨德里克的死刑
Doing this is effectively sentencing Hendrik to death.
换做我们其中任何人  他也会这样做的
He would do the same thing to any of us!
绝不犹豫
In heartbeat!
这是唯一的选择
This is only option.
如果还有机会呢
What if it's also an opportunity?
什么机会
To do what?
杀斯莱德的机会
To kill Slade.
我知道我有一阵子没来了
I know that I haven't been here in a while,
但你看起来不像是整个董事会成员吧
but you don't look like the entire board of directors.
会议半小时后才开始
The meeting doesn't start for another half hour.
真的吗
Really?
我照例把所有预约的时间提前了30分钟
I routinely bump all appointments 30 minutes
考虑到你经常迟到
in anticipation of you being late.
这办法不错
It's good policy.
但谢谢你为此不再冬眠了
But, thank you for coming out of hibernation for this.
不管你有没有意识到  大楼上是你的名字
Whether you recognize it or not, it's your name on the building,
不管你缺席多少次会议
and no matter how many meetings you miss,
你依旧是公司的代言人
you're still the public face of this company.
伊莎贝尔  我知道最近无暇顾及公司
Isabel, I realize I have been distracted.
谢谢你帮我收拾烂摊子
Thank you for picking up the slack.
虽然我们是非传统的合伙人
Ours is an unconventional partnership,
但也是合伙人
but it's a partnership.
而且很有效
And it's working.
的确是
Indeed it is.
奥利弗
Oliver...
你母亲来了
Your mother's here.
家庭矛盾吗
Family squabble?
罗切夫女士最近怎么样
And how is Ms. Rochev these days?
还在因为自己家人的事生气吗
Still angry that Dorothy dropped a house on her sister?
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
-你跟西娅联系过吗  -没有
- Have you heard from Thea? - No.
你没有回我电话
You haven't returned any of my phone calls,
所以我没有办法只能当面找你
so I'm left to resort to checking in person
问你参不参加今晚的辩论会
as to whether you're attending the debate tonight.
我说过我在公开场合会支持你竞选的
I told you that I would publicly support your campaign.
还有事吗
Anything else?
如果你今晚都不能有个好儿子的样子
It would be embarrassing for us both
那我们俩都会很尴尬的
if you couldn't at least appear to be my son tonight.
我很擅长伪装成别的样子
I have gotten pretty good at pretending to be someone I'm not.
我跟你学的
I learned it from you.
打扰了  你看见西娅·奎恩了吗
Oh, excuse me, have you seen Thea Queen?
好吧
OK.
闪电妞  我是奥利  我在辩论会这里
Speedy, it's Ollie, and I'm at the debate,
我以为你也在呢
where I thought you would be.
我知道罗伊的事你很难过
Listen, I know that you're upset about Roy,
但妈妈需要我们两个都来
but mom needs both of us here.
所以拜托了  回我电话
So please, just call me back.
你看起来不是很开心  一切还好吗
You do not look happy. Is everything all right?
是的  我的妹妹有点迟到了
Yes. My sister's just a little late.
我想这可能是因为我
I'm afraid that's my fault.
星城警局坚持车队开道让我过来
SCPD insisted that I arrive with a motorcade.
这阻碍了全市的交通
We tied up traffic all over the city.
西娅肯定是被堵在路上了
I'm sure Thea's probably just fallen victim to gridlock.
我再给她打个电话试试
Well, I should probably try her again.
祝你今晚好运  塞巴斯蒂安
Good luck tonight, Sebastian.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
我以为后台是闲人免进的
I thought backstage was supposed to be restricted access.
我想这就是做地区检察官的好处吧
The benefits of having a district attorney's badge, I guess.
你来祝莫伊拉好运吗
You stop by to wish Moira good luck?
是的  但我很高兴碰到了你
I did. But I'm really glad I ran into you.
我应该向你道歉
I owe you an apology.
我曾指责你做了很多糟糕的事
I accused you of really terrible things.
你当时正处在一个非常艰难的时期
You were going through a very difficult time.
我很高兴你慢慢恢复了
I'm just happy you're on the mend.
祝你今晚好运
Good luck tonight.
今晚需要运气的可不是我
I'm not the one who's going to need it.
塞巴斯蒂安·布拉德不是你们想的那样
Sebastian Blood is not the man you think he is.
他不会通过社会服务使城市复兴
He's not going to revive the city with social services.
星城市长竞选辩论
2014年度竞选
没有资金支持的委任会让城市破产
He's going to bankrupt it with unfunded mandates.
奎恩女士对我竞选的不满是
Mrs. Queen's problem with my proposals
这一切都由那1%的富人买单
is that they will be paid for by the one percent.
是时候让富人们
It's time that the wealthiest
担起自己的责任了
people stop avoiding their responsibility.
但这会限制他们选人用人的能力
But it will limit their abilities to hire people.
好了  时间到  我提醒候选人
All right, that's time, and I will remind the candidates
请不要再打断对方
to please refrain from interrupting.
接下来是下一位星城选民
Now we have the next in our series of video questions
通过视频提出的问题
submitted by Starling City voters.
来自...西娅·奎恩
This one comes from... Thea Queen.
一定是出错了
Ok, there must be some mistake.
救命
Help!
救命  来人救救我  拜托
Help! Somebody help me, please!
他  斯莱...
He--sla--
天啊
Oh, my God!
西娅·奎恩的生命对你来说值多少钱
我们会找到她的  罗伊  我们会救她回来的
We're going to find her, Roy. We're going to get her back.
她是个坚强的女孩
She's a tough girl.
我们找到她的时候她还会活着吗
Is she going to be alive when we find her?
你不能这么想
You can't think like that.
我没办法不这么想
I can't stop thinking like that.
狄格尔先生
Mr. Diggle.
Mr. Diggle!
我好像有发现  正在查
I think I might have found something. I'm working on it.
我暂停竞选  贡献一切资源
I am suspending my campaign and devoting its resources
西娅·奎恩遭绑架
希望西娅·奎恩能安全回来
to the safe return of Thea Queen.
今天  是我们...
Today, the day we both...
视频上提到了要求  但没提到赎金
Well, the video referenced a demand, but no ransom,
所以说这可能不是钱的事
which means this might not be about money.
我们会救她回来的  莫伊拉
We're going to get her back, Moira.
我向你保证  西娅会回家的
I promise you. Thea's coming home.
你想想有没有人
Now, can you think of anyone
会想通过西娅来威胁你
who might want to get to you through Thea?
去年死去的那503个人的家属都有可能
No one except for the families of the 503 people that died last year.
这跟地震没有关系
This isn't about the quake.
你怎么能确定
Well, how can you be so sure?
你们只需要找到那个戴面具的人
You just need to find the man in the mask!
我们在找
Look, we're working on it.
我们在追踪每一条线索
We're running down every lead.
什么线索
What are those leads?
天啊
Oh, God!
天啊  我怎么会让这种事发生
Oh, God, how could I have let this happen?
失陪一下
Excuse me for a minute.
如果再让我知道有一个
If I hear about one more
有攻击性的媒体调查传送到奎恩先生
invasive press inquiry being sent to Mr. Queen
或者奎恩家的任何家庭成员面前
or to any member of the Queen family,
我就唯你是问
I will hold you personally responsible.
你这样很吓人啊  谢谢你
You're very scary. Thank you.
我的工作是帮你处理事务  今天尤甚
My job is to take things off your plate, now more than ever.
说到这个  你还记得在今天董事会上
To that end, you remember how at today's meeting,
董事成员提名的新管理人员吗
the board nominated new officers?
投票需要在24小时之内进行
Voting has to take place within 24 hours.
美国证监会在看着呢  不能耽搁
It cannot be suspended. It's an SEC thing.
我现在没心思想这个
I can't think about this right now.
我明白  我很遗憾  但是你必须要想
I know, and I'm sorry, but you have to.
你是公司的总裁  你有责任...
You're the CEO and you have responsibilities--
一直都是你替我负责的
Which you handle for me all the time.
董事会投票与替你出席会议
A board vote is several orders of magnitude, different
是完全不同的
from covering a missed meeting.
你可以临时任命一位总裁
You could appoint someone CEO pro tempore.
不过那不是个好主意
That's not a good idea.
我现在就任命你
I'm appointing you.
什么
What?
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你现在是临时总裁
You are the temporary CEO.
不行
I can't.
求你了
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
等西娅安全回家了  让她谢谢我
Have Thea thank me, when she's back safe at home.
奎恩先生  我需要和你谈谈威尔逊的事
Mr. Queen? I need to talk to you, it's about Mr. Wilson.
西娅最后被看见是在威登酒吧
Since the last place Thea was seen was Verdant,
我通过信用卡记录列出了昨晚客人的名单
I used credit card receipts, compiled a list of customers last night,
追踪了他们的电话  黑进去看了他们的照片
pinged all their cell phones and hacked into their photos.
美国国家安全局是对的
The NSA is right;
不用申请批准确实方便多了
it's a lot easier when you don't need a warrant.
我浏览了所有照片
I eyeballed every photo.
那得有几千张照片
There must have been thousands.
为了西娅  我找到了这个
It's Thea. I found this.
在离酒吧三个街区处发现的部分车牌
Partial plate three blocks from the club.
车子是在斯莱德·威尔逊名下的
Car's registered to a Slade Wilson,
车里有定位导航系统
and it has GPS.
现在车在哪里
Where is it right now?
停在罗斯福街的一间倒闭的酒吧外
Parked outside a defunct bar on Roosevelt.
你不觉得这样太容易了吗
Ok, this doesn't seem easy to you?
斯莱德在自己的名下注册了一辆车
Slade using a car registered in his name?
整件事都很诡异
The whole thing smells rotten.
无论是西娅还是他在那里
Either Thea's there or he is.
我们都得去看看
Either way, we have to go.
我就知道你会这么说
Yeah, I figured you'd say that,
所以我已经提炼好了这个
which is why I worked up these.
西藏蝮蛇毒
Tibetan pit viper venom.
刺客联盟的人一直用它
The league of assassins' poison of choice.
是我用过的最有效的镇定剂
And the most powerful sedative that I've ever worked with.
那会给我们带来优势
That'll give us an advantage.
而你是我们的另一个优势
But you are going to give us another.
你确定要我跟着去吗
Are you sure you want me to go?
你愤怒吗  利用你的愤怒吧
Are you angry? Use that rage.
你一直都让我隐忍行事
Well, you're just always telling me to hold back.
今晚不用
Not tonight.
炸弹吗
Landmines?
这个岛是个什么地方啊
What kind of island is this?
你会拆弹吗
Can you remove the explosive?
当然会
Certainly.
能不能在不引爆的情况下拆除
Without it going off, eh.
就不那么确定了
Less certain.
克格勃  我在那学到很多很多东西
Ah, KGB. You taught me many, many things.
无论俄国炸弹
Russian bomb,
还是日本炸弹
Japanese bomb;
它们都会...嘭
they both go...boom.
恭喜  我们还活着  现在要怎么做
Congratulations, we are not dead. Now what?
我们按照约定让斯莱德带走亨德里克
Well, Slade takes Hendrik as we agreed.
等他们走得够远的时候...
And then once they're far enough away...
怎么
What--
你想把炸弹放到亨德里克身上
You want to rig Hendrik into bomb?
彼得说得没错  把亨德里克交给斯莱德
Well, Peter was right. Handing Hendrik over to Slade
就等于杀了他  你说得也没错
is the same thing as killing him. And you're right, too.
我们别无选择  不过  这样至少
We don't have a choice. I mean, at least this way,
可以把斯莱德除掉
he can take out Slade,
那样我们就可以登船了
and then we can take the ship.
怎么了
What?
只是  好奇
Just...wondering.
你什么时候变得如此可怕了
When did you become so scary?
她在哪里  斯莱德
Where is she, Slade?
他在问你问题
The man asked you a question.
她在哪里
Where is she?
你要把我怎么样  小子  杀了我吗
What are you going to do, kid? Kill me?
那样的话谁会告诉你
But then who would tell you...
你亲爱的妹妹在什么地方
where your beloved Thea is?
打电话给兰斯警探
Call detective Lance.
叫他来这里
Tell him to come down here.
什么  为什么
Wh--what? Why?
来逮捕斯莱德·威尔逊
To arrest Slade Wilson.
你知道这个混蛋为什么抓西娅·奎恩吗
Any idea what this son of a bitch wants with Thea Queen?
不知道  我们只需要
No. We just need to make
让斯莱德说出他把西娅关在哪里就行
sure that Slade gives up where he's holding her.
奥利弗知道吗
Does Oliver know?
这件事是你跟绿箭侠一起行动的
That you're working with the Arrow on this?
绿箭侠的事奥利弗什么都不知道
Oliver doesn't know anything about the Arrow.
你还好吗
Hey, are you OK?
我没事  就是莫伊拉现在的眼神
Yeah. It's just that look in Moira's eyes
害怕已经失去女儿的那种眼神
terrified she's lost her daughter.
那种感觉我无法承受第二次了  莎拉
I couldn't go through that again, Sara.
兰斯警官
Officer Lance?
奎恩家的人到了
The Queen family's here.
兰斯先生  他告诉你西娅在哪了吗
Mr. Lance, did he tell you where Thea is?
奎恩夫人  谢谢你过来
Mrs. Queen, thank you for coming.
这实在是讲不通
This doesn't make any sense.
斯莱德·威尔逊是我们的朋友
Slade Wilson is a friend.
而且他过去的72小时都在哥斯达黎加
And he's been in Costa Rica for the past 72 hours.
他有乘客名单证明  通话记录
He can provide flight manifests, phone records,
甚至还有录像证明
even some videos,
所以不可能是他抓了您女儿
so he couldn't have taken your daughter.
如果不是他  为什么要把他抓来
If he didn't, then why did you arrest him?
不是我们抓的  是治安维持者把他抓住的
We didn't. He was apprehended by the vigilante.
然后联系了兰斯警官
Who then contacted officer Lance.
局长  我可以解释...
Lieutenant, I can explain--
不  我想我很清楚是怎么回事
No, I think I got a pretty clear picture.
天啊  你可真不是一般的笨
God, you're a special kind of stupid.
你不戴警徽而穿那套制服的
The whole reason you're wearing that uniform
唯一原因
instead of a detective's shield
是因为你跟治安维持者同流合污了
is 'cause you were working with the vigilante.
一个小女孩失踪了  而你却
A young girl is missing, and you just--
现在你就因为他一声令下而逮捕了某人吗
And now you arrest someone on his say-so?
如果你下一个穿的制服
You'll be lucky if the next uniform
不是囚服  你就该庆幸了
that puts you in isn't prison gray.
他们都叫你丧钟
They're calling you Deathstroke.
有点儿太高调了
It's a bit flamboyant.
我很喜欢
I like it.
你怎么从岛上逃出来的
How did you get off the island?
这就是你问我的第一个问题吗
That is your first question?
你已经清楚表明
Well, you've made it pretty clear
绝不会告诉我妹妹的下落
that you're not going to tell me where my sister is,
所以没错  这是我问你的第一个问题
so, yeah. That's my first question.
我游出来的
I swam.
但那也是经历了千辛万苦的
But it wasn't without its obstacles.
激流想把我淹没
The rip current dragged me under.
暗礁上的石头让我皮开肉绽
The rocks on the reef cut up my flesh to the bone.
但是米拉库鲁
But the Mirakuru...
让一切都再生了
It regenerated everything.
除了这只眼
Except this.
这房间里只有我们两个人
You know, it's just the two of us in here,
所以你说实话吧
so why don't we try being honest?
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
你知道为什么
You know why.
那是五年前的事了
It was five years ago.
犹如昨天
It was yesterday.
我试着想放开岛上的事
Oh, I tried to let go of the island...
但记忆依旧缠着我
but it's still got a hold on me.
如果你每晚都穿的兜帽是某种象征的话
And if that hood that you wear every night is any indication,
记忆也还缠着你啊  孩子
it's still got a hold of you, kid.
她对你什么都没做  是我做的
She never did anything to you. I did.
莎朵是因为我所做的选择而死
Shado is dead because of a choice that I made.
所以惩罚我  责怪我
So punish me. Blame me.
但是
But...
西娅
Thea.
你想让我求你吗
You want me to beg?
这就是你的目的吗  让我求你
Is that what this all about? Because I'm begging.
你赢了
You win.
求你了
Just, please...
请告诉我她在哪儿
Please tell me where she is.
你能这样说一定很不容易
Hmm, that must have been hard for you to say.
西娅
Thea...
西娅在...
Well, Thea's--
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.
谁让你进来的
Who the hell let you in here?
威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson...
你可以走了
you are free to go,
警局对此深表歉意
with the department's deepest apologies.
不用  警督
There's no need, lieutenant.
一名无辜的女孩生死未卜
An innocent girl's life hangs in the balance.
你需要追查一切有希望的线索
You need to follow every lead possible.
但你还是应该知道兰斯警官
Well, still, you should know that Officer Lance
会面对很严重的指控
is facing some very serious charges.
别以我的名义起诉他们
Well, don't pursue them on my behalf.
我可不是会记仇的人
I'm not one to hold a grudge.
威尔逊先生  威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson, Mr. Wilson,
警方已经撤销对你的所有指控了吗
have the police cleared you of all charges?
我当时在哥斯达黎加  但一听到这个噩耗
I was in Costa Rica, but returned to Starling City
就立刻回到了星城
as soon as I heard the terrible news.
关于西娅·奎恩的失踪  你是怎么跟他们说的
What did you tell them about Thea Queen's disappearance?
我向他们提供了我所能支配的一切资源
I'm offering every resource at my disposal,
再加上五百万美元悬赏
plus a $5 million reward
以求任何关于绑架西娅·奎恩的人的消息
for any information that leads to Thea Queen's captors.
我是狄格  我正跟着他
This is Dig, I've got the follow.
在他车上安的追踪器运转正常
Tracker on his car is active.
罗伊  他正往你那边过去
Roy, he's coming up on your position.
看到他了  他拐入了沃纳街
Got him. He's turning up Warner.
看到了  正往北方走
I see him. Heading north.
该死  我跟丢了
Damn it, I lost him!
没事  我还跟着他
It's all right. I still have eyes on him.
莎拉  右转去唐尼街
Sara, cut right onto Downey.
明白
Got 'em.
不是  不是  不是他的车
Negative. Negative, it's not him!
什么
What?!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
他克隆了追踪器的信号
He's cloned the tracker's signal.
罗伊  你得赶快移动
Roy, you've got to move!
罗伊  你得在福勒街上追踪到他
Roy, you got to pick him up on Fuller.
罗伊  你还跟着他吗
Roy, do you still have eyes on him?
罗伊
Roy?
Roy!
出去
Leave us.
对不起我离开了这么久
Sorry I was gone for so long.
去死吧
Screw you.
我看见奥利弗和你母亲了
I saw Oliver and your mother.
他们都非常担心你
They're all quite worried about you.
如果你敢伤害他们  我发誓我要...
If you hurt them, I swear I--
请继续说
Please. Go on.
把那句话说完
Finish that sentence.
我很好奇一个十九岁的女孩
I'm curious to know what kind of threat
能做出什么样的威胁
a 19-year-old girl can make.
你想要我怎么样
What do you want with me?
这个嘛  西娅
Well, that, Thea...
说来话长
is a very long story.
看来我有的是时间
Looks like I've got time.
并没有
Not at all.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
什么
What?
我只是要表明我的态度
I had to make a point,
目的达到了
and I made it.
门没锁
The door is unlocked,
你什么时候想离开都可以
so you can leave any time you'd like.
但那些为你工作的人
But those guys who work for you
我一走出去就会朝我开枪
will shoot me the second I walk out.
他们不会的
No, they won't.
他们的任务只是在我回来之前看住你
Their instructions were to keep you here until I returned.
现在我已经回来了  所以
And I have. So...
你可以离开了
you're free to go.
但一旦你走了
But, if you do,
就永远不会知道你哥哥的秘密了
you may never know about your brother's secret.
什么
What?
你哥哥有一个秘密  西娅
Your brother has a secret, Thea.
想知道是什么吗
Would you like to know what it is?
所以
So...
现在该怎么做
what now?
等奥利弗
Wait for Oliver.
想想下一步该怎么做
Figure out what our next move will be.
你是说等他的命令吧
Wait for him to tell us, you mean.
没有奎恩国王的圣旨我们什么也不能做
We can't do anything without King Queen's permission.
你话说过头了  罗伊
You're out of line, Roy.
好了  大家都冷静一下
All right, let's all just calm down here.
斯莱德暂占上风  这是兵家常事
Slade outplayed us. It happens.
不  都怪警察放走了斯莱德
No, it only happened because the police let Slade go--
而那是奥利弗叫我们把他送进去的
after we turned him in, because Oliver told us to.
不然我们该怎么做呢
What were we supposed to do?
你是特种部队的
You're Special Forces.
她是个跨国杀手
She's an international assassin.
凭我们三个
You would think between the three of us,
不把他交给警察
we could have gotten answers
我们也就逼出答案了
out of Slade ourselves instead of turning him into the police.
最恶心的是  他说要这么做
Here's what's really sick; is we didn't even question him
我们都没有人质疑是不是应该如此
because he said it was the right thing to do.
就像他说我该和西娅分手
Just like he said that I needed to break up with Thea
而一周之前
one week after telling me
他还告诉我让西娅一个人不安全
that it wasn't safe for me to leave her alone--
等等
Wait!
难道你觉得斯莱德抓走西娅是奥利弗的错
You think it's oliver's fault that Slade took Thea?
我认为我没能阻止斯莱德是他的错
I think it was his fault that I wasn't there to stop Slade.
我认为你只是因为跟丢了斯莱德而迁怒于他
And I think you're just blaming Oliver because you lost Slade.
你们正搞在一起  你当然帮他说话了
Well, of course you'd take his side, you're screwing him.
能让我们单独待一会吗
Can you guys give us a minute, please?
你记不记得她多爱画画
Do you remember how she loved to color?
你爸爸一箱一箱地给她买蜡笔
Your father would buy her boxes of crayons by the truckload.
却总是满足不了她
She could never get enough.
她老在墙上画画
She'd draw on the walls.
我却总生不起气来  因为画得那么可爱
And I could never get angry, because it was just so adorable.
你应该去休息一下
You should try to get some sleep.
我的宝贝还活着吗
Is my baby still alive?
什么
What?
我的宝贝还活着吗
Is my baby still alive?
是的
Yes.
我忍受了丧子之痛整整五年
I woke up every day for five years the mother who lost her son.
我不能
I-- I can't...
我不能再承受一次了
I can't endure it again.
现在你对我恨之入骨
And now you hate me,
而且并非是无理取闹
and you have every justification.
-现在不合适  -就是现在
- Now is not the time. - Yes, it is.
这是最好的时机
It is exactly the time.
我告诉过你那些欺骗
I've told you that these lies
是为了保护家人
were to keep our family safe;
让我们团结
to keep us all together,
但那就是最大的谎言
but that was the biggest lie of all.
我用它欺骗了你  西娅
And I told it to you, to Thea,
和我自己
to myself.
因为我太脆弱
Because I was too weak
不能面对真相
to face any kind of truth.
现在发生的事不是你的错
What's happening now isn't your fault.
从子女出生起
From the moment your children are born,
你就担心世界会不会伤害他们
you worry what the world might do to them.
但你从没想过自己会不会伤害他们
But you never stop to think what you might do to them.
我们可能就是自己最大的敌人
That we could be our own worst enemy.
奥利
Ollie!
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
不足挂齿
Not enough.
你又对他做了什么
And what did you do to him?
我们把他打晕了  这样比较方便
We just knocked him. It's better that way.
他不太赞成这场交易
He wasn't exactly a fan of the arrangement.
可想而知
I would imagine.
亨德里克是你的了
Hendrik's all yours.
我知道
I know.
等等
Wait.
米拉库鲁真个很神奇的东西
It's an incredible thing, this Mirakuru.
它不仅给了我力量
Not only does it give you strength,
还强化了我的感官
it also heightens all of your senses.
炸药有一种特殊的味道
TNT has a particular smell.
还有多久爆炸
How long before it goes off?
90秒
90 seconds?
还是60秒
60 seconds?
你们可能以为爆炸能杀死我
You're probably thinking that the blast would kill me,
我可不这么认为
but I disagree.
不过你们就不一样了
Not that I could say the same for you lot.
我迫不及待
I am tempted
想看到你被炸成碎片
to see this blow you to pieces.
不过话说回来  也许我可以直接杀死你
But then again, maybe I'll just shoot you
就像他杀死莎朵一样
the same way that he shot Shado.
不
No.
斯莱德
Slade...
你要去哪里
Hey, where are you going?
干坐在这里可帮不了西娅  不是吗
Well, sitting around here isn't helping Thea, now is it?
你这样鲁莽行事是不行的 罗伊
Neither is you running off half-cocked, Roy.
我知道你们认为
I know that you think
是米拉库鲁在影响我  但并非如此
that this is the Mirakuru, but it's not.
我是对的  你也清楚
I'm right, and you know that I am.
所以你最好别他妈挡着我
So you better get the hell out of my way.
罗伊  冷静点
Roy, just calm down.
西娅也会希望我们这么做的
It's what Thea would want us to do.
她说的对  罗伊  我们先按兵不动
She's right, Roy. Come on, let's throttle back.
下一箭会直穿你的心脏
Next one goes into your chest.
放开他
Let him go.
你真的要因为
You would honestly kill me because I dare
我批评全能的奥利弗·奎恩而杀我吗
to criticize the almighty Oliver Queen?
不  我杀你是因为你正在伤害我的朋友
No, I'd kill you because you're hurting my friend.
放开他
Let him go.
Let him go!
这下面到底怎么回事
What the hell's going on down here?
我不干了
I'm done.
就这么回事
That's what's going on.
西娅在外头受伤了或是更糟  因为一个人
Thea, she's out there, hurt or worse, because of one person.
而那个人不是斯莱德·威尔逊
And that is not Slade Wilson.
罗伊
Roy...
我曾那么信任你
I believed in you.
我已经没有理由留下了
There's nothing left for me here.
-我的天  奥利弗  -又怎么了
- Oh, my god. Oliver... - Now what?
宣传部起草了一份很有力的声明
Publicity has drafted a rather compelling statement,
我会去参加脱口秀来引导舆论导向
and I will be doing the talk show rounds to control the spin.
我很抱歉  罗切夫女士  但他很
I'm sorry, Ms. Rochev, but he was very...
急迫
insistent.
你们先出去吧
Can you give us the room, please?
伊莎贝尔  你干了什么
Isabel, what have you done?
我吗  没做什么
Me? Very little.
你让我当上总裁之时
You're the one who made this possible
就让这一切有了可能
when you made me CEO.
我知道只是暂时的
I know it was only temporary,
但给了我所需要的权限
but it gave me the authority I needed
来召集紧急董事会
to call an emergency board meeting.
就在半小时前
As of 30 minutes ago,
你的公司归我了
your company belongs to me.
董事们一致同意将我的任命变成永久性的
The directors unanimously made my appointment permanent.
我本来想说他们对你的领导力失去了信任
I'd say they lost faith in your leadership,
不过那样听起来就好像你有领导力似的
but that would imply there was any.
也许你应该少花点精力在你的
Maybe you should have focused a little less on your...
晚间活动上
evening activities.
斯莱德
Slade...
你为他工作
You're working for him.
和他工作
With.
他知道把我安插进你的家族企业
He knew planting me in your family's business
会把你拉回星城
would draw you back to Starling City.
说实话  我很怀疑  但是
Truth be told, I was skeptical, but...
为什么你要这么做
Why are you doing this?!
你不知道还真是可悲
I think it's sad you don't know.
父债子还
The sins of the father are the sins of the son.
快告诉我  我妹妹在哪里
You are going to tell me where my sister is,
否则我就杀了你
or I am going to kill you.
她在哪儿
Where is she?!
他把她关在一个货站里
He's holding her at a storage depot
就在市区边上  托斯卡货运
just outside the city limits. Tosca Cartage.
我怎么知道你不是在骗我
How do I know you're not lying?!
你真可爱  你还不知道吧
It's cute how you think this isn't all playing out
事情进展正像他所希望的那样
exactly how he wants it to.
而且他要你一个人去
And he wants you to come alone.
如果他嗅到了你搭档的气息
If he even smells your partners,
他会把小西娅像条鲑鱼一样开膛破肚
he will gut sweet little Thea like a trout.
跟你共事很愉快  奥利弗
It was a pleasure doing business with you, Oliver.
至少让我们包围周边地区
At least let us surround the perimeter.
不  伊莎贝尔说的很明白
No, Isabel was very clear.
我一个人去  否则西娅性命难保
I come alone or Thea dies.
奥利  这是斯莱德的又一个游戏  除非
Ollie, this is another one of Slade's games, and unless--
不  我什么都做不了  莎拉
No, what I can't do, Sara, is nothing!
如果是劳蕾尔你会怎么做
What would you do if it were Laurel,
如果是你的父亲或者母亲呢
or your father, or your mother?
我不想一次又一次陷入同样的争论之中
I will not get dragged into the same debate over and over again!
去吧
Go.
去找到西娅
Go get Thea.
阻止斯莱德
Stop Slade.
做你该做的
Do whatever it takes.
彻底解决问题
End this once and for all.
停车  停车
Stop, stop!
万圣节已经过去半年了  傻帽
Halloween was six months ago, ass hat.
滚开  不然就毙了你  听到了吗
Now get off the road or get put down. You hear me?
我有个提议给你们
I have a proposal for you men.
-说  -奥利弗  你没事吧
- Go! - Oliver, are you ok?
我没事  但西娅不在这里
Yeah, I'm fine, but Thea's not here.
-你做到了  -做到什么了
- You did it. - Did what?
西娅没事  她没事
Thea's fine. She's fine.
她五分钟前走进了分局
She walked into the precinct five minutes ago.
安然无恙
Safe and sound.
奥利弗  你听到了吗
Oliver, did you hear me?
-西娅呢  -她没事  没受伤
- Thea? - She's fine, no injuries.
-他没碰她  -他不在那里
- He didn't touch her. - He wasn't there.
-他手下很多雇佣兵  -他不在那里
- He had a lot of men, hired guns. - He wasn't there.
因为他正在别处忙活
Because he was busy elsewhere.
铁山监狱重新启用了一批地震中毁掉的牢房
Iron Heights reopened a wing damaged in the quake.
有一辆运囚车被斯莱德劫持了
There was a prisoner transfer. Slade hijacked it.
为他的军队招募士兵
Soldiers for his army.
绑架西娅只是调虎离山
Abducting Thea was all a diversion.
奥利弗
Oliver!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
我的宝贝
Oh, my baby!
Ohh! My baby.
怎么了
What?
他告诉我了
He told me.
威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson...
他把你的秘密告诉我了
He told me your secret.
这些年你是怎么骗我的
How you've been lying to me for years.
你怎能不告诉我  马尔科姆·梅林是我父亲
How could you not tell me Malcolm Merlyn was my father?!
我那么信任你
I believed in you.
我们是想保证你的安全
We were trying to keep you safe.
你知道你这样听起来像谁吗
Do you have any idea who you sound like?
听起来像她
You sound like her.
斯莱德
Slade...
死亡太便宜他们了
Death's too good for them.
这个岛就是对他们的惩罚
This island should be their punishment.
死亡太便宜你们了
Death is too good for you.
这个岛就是对你们的惩罚
This island should be your punishment.
是他们余生的牢笼
Their prison for the rest of their days.
是你们余生的牢笼
Your prison for the rest of your days.
带他走
Get him out of here.
斯莱德
Slade...
回去
Get back!
我可以帮你
I can help you.
是生  是死
You can live, or you can die.
你自己选
You choose.
你想给自己的家人捎点消息吗
Would you like to send a message to your family?
船修好之后我就去拜访他们
'Cause as soon as this boat is fixed, I'm paying them a visit.
星城地界  您已出城
漫长的一夜啊
Hell of a night.
昆汀·兰斯  说话真委婉啊
Quentin Lance, master of the understatement.
借一步说话  警官
A word, officer?
稍等  亲爱的
Hold on, sweetheart.
怎么了
Yeah?
我已经跟斯宾塞地检官说过你的情况了
I've spoken to DA Spencer about your...situation.
她不想起诉...
She doesn't want to press charges--
前提是你合作
if you cooperate.
告诉我们治安维持者在哪里
Tell us where the vigilante is.
我也想告诉你们  可我不知道
Well, I'd love to, but I don't know.
那就太不幸了
Well, that's unfortunate.
看样子是的
Yeah, it looks like.
昆汀·拉里·兰斯  你因为
Quentin Larry Lance, you're under arrest
参与谋划帮助罪犯等多项罪名被捕
for conspiracy and aiding in multiple felonies.
搞什么  你疯了吗
What? Are you out of your mind?!
你干什么呢  威尔逊  是威尔逊干的
What are you doing? Wilson--Wilson did it!
我抓对人了  你...
I collared the right guy. What are you--
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
-你有权找律师协助  -爸爸
- You have the right to an attorney. - Dad!
虽然有专家称这是大打同情牌
Riding what pundits are calling a sympathy bump,
但是莫伊拉·奎恩在昨天
Moira Queen pulled far ahead of Sebastian Blood
刚进行的投票中  远远领先
in the latest polls conducted in
塞巴斯蒂安·布拉德...
the last 24 hours by channel--
竟然就这样搞砸了
The whole thing just blew up in my face!
这让我还怎么当选
How the hell do I get elected now?!
你是不是该换种语气跟我说话
I think you intended a different tone.
你说过我会成为市长的
You said I'd be mayor!
你就这样把成果拱手让给
And you just delivered this election
莫伊拉·奎恩了  为什么
for Moira Queen, and for what?
你跟奎恩家族的人到底有什么关系
What is this obsession you have with the Queen family?
你没跟他说吗
You haven't told him?
你答应过我的
You promised me.
我说过会把星城给你
I promised you this city.
我还说过给你一支军队让你夺取星城
I promised you an army with which to take it.
现在什么情况
What is our status?
奎恩联合企业的应用科学部门
Queen Consolidated's applied sciences division
正在全力
is now fully dedicated to
用你的血样复制血清
replicating a serum based on your blood sample.
看到了吧
You see...
一切皆在掌握之中
Everything is proceeding as planned.
你要去哪里
Where are you going now?
去处理一下我的目标
To service my obsession.
得再让奥利弗·奎恩分分神
Oliver Queen needs one more distraction.
你们两个在这里干什么
What are you two doing here?
我们想着你会来这里
We thought this is where you would go.
这个不难猜  你最近一直
You're predictable. That, and you've been
都在这里的小床上过夜
sleeping on the cot at night.
你们到底想干什么
What are you doing here?
要不我们去哪里
Where else would we be?
罗伊是对的
Roy was right.
每次转折点上  我都会作出错误的决定
At every turn, I had made the wrong decision.
对他
With him,
对公司  还有...
with...the company, and...
对西娅
and with Thea.
我太专注于斯莱德对我的所作所为
I was so focused on what Slade might do to me,
以至于我...
that it never...
从没想过自己会对自己作出什么事
even occurred to me what I could do to myself.
我才是自己最大的敌人
I am my own worst enemy.
那是斯莱德说的  奥利弗  不要轻信他的话
That's Slade talking, Oliver. Don't let him in your head.
他在我的脑海中挥之不去  狄格尔
I can't keep him out of my head, Diggle!
我...  我阻止不了他做任何事情
I can't...I can't stop him from doing anything.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
你凭什么这么确定
What makes you so sure?
因为有我们在
Because you're not alone, man.
现在干什么  老大
Now what, boss?
现在我们反击
Now we fight back.
警方签发了针对斯莱德·威尔逊的拘捕令
Police have issued a warrant for Slade Wilson
因为西娅·奎恩指证
after Thea Queen named him
他是绑架她的幕后黑手
as the mastermind of her kidnapping yesterday.
这是奎恩小姐被释放  而威尔逊被捕
This in the wake of Wilson's arrest and subsequent release
然后又被星城警方释放后几个小时后的情况
by the SCPD hours before Ms. Queen was released.
在向媒体的声明中
In a statement to the press,
星城警署局长富兰克林·派克
SCPD lieutenant Franklin Pike
重申了自己对警局方面的支持
reiterated his support for his department
虽然这件事显而易见是警方乌龙了
despite what appears to be a serious blunder.
他还说  星城警署有责任...
He went on to say, the SCPD is committed--
确保对任何人的逮捕都符合法律规定
to making sure any arrest they make is a legal one,
但是没有充分证据...
but without sufficient--
不用害怕
Don't worry.
我不是来伤害你的
I am not here to harm you.
去死吧
Go to hell!
人终有一死
All in good time, I'm sure.
但是我死前
But before then,
我要来星城
I have come to Starling City
看到奥利弗·奎恩痛苦
to see Oliver Queen suffer.
奥利弗...  什么
Oliver...what?
为什么
Why?
因为你根本不知道他的真面目
Because he's not the man you think he is.
你怎么知道
And how would you know that?
因为我知道奥利弗·奎恩就是...
Because I know Oliver Queen is...
绿箭侠
The Arrow.